{"description":"A set of questions to test the software with","name":"Pilot All","version":1,"questions":[{"question":"1. To determine an individual aircraft\u2019s maximum payload weight:","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para: 1 -8","responses":["Add Operating Weight to Maximum Ramp Weight","Add Operating Weight to Maximum Zero Fuel Weight","Subtract Operating Weight from Maximum Zero Fuel Weight","Subtract Operating Weight from Maximum Ramp Weight"]},{"question":"2. Low EGT margin engines are more susceptible to ENG EGT X alerts on the WAP when OAT is at or above and \tthrust is at or near maximum thrust?","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para: 1 -89 A","responses":["24 *C (75 *F)","20 *C (68 *F)","18 *C (65 *F)","27 *C (81 *F)"]},{"question":"3. The AP has two modes of operation; _____, and _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para: 1 -1162B","responses":["TAKEOFF, MSN","normal, AP DEGRADED","standard, decluttered","MSN, PROF "]},{"question":"4. AP DEGRADED mode will not engage below Vmma with invalid aircraft weights (both MC\u2019s inop, etc).","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-1184B(W)","responses":["TRUE","FALSE "]},{"question":"5. THRUST LOSS annunciator lights (amber) will illuminate in flight when thrust of a single engine is _____ less than the average EPR of the remaining engines.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para: 1 -100(N)","responses":["0.10 EPR","0.15 EPR","0.20 EPR","0.25 EPR "]},{"question":"6. In the event of boost pump failure, fuel can be suction fed by the engine driven fuel pump at _____ thrust rating up to an altitude of _____ feet and at a pitch angle no greater than 21.5 degrees.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-117","responses":["MAX; 20,000","INT; 20,000","MAX; 10,000","INT; 10,000"]},{"question":"7. The engine starting system can be used in flight as well as on the ground.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-124","responses":["TRUE","FALSE "]},{"question":"8. The starter is designed to start the engine with normal starting loads. Excessive loads are applied when the engine driven hydraulic pumps are on. A may result if the pumps are on during engine start.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-125(N)","responses":["Hot Start","Hung Start","Cold Start","Buddy Start "]},{"question":"9. Engine Start Buttons: The button will stay in until engine N2 RPM reaches approximately _____ percent.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-127","responses":["18","30","51","55"]},{"question":"10. The APU AUTO SHUT DN ORIDE switchlight will override all automatic shutdowns except _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-161","responses":["an indicated Fire or overspeed","a fire and high EGT","High EGT and overspeed","Low oil press and high EGT "]},{"question":"11. To trigger an engine or APU fire annunciation,","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-188","responses":["Both loops must be subjected simultaneously to fire for the warning system to be energized.","Only one of the loops must be exposed to a fire","The fire detector control unit must be heated to a specific temperature and then the unit will energize the warning system","The entire length of the sensing element must be exposed to direct flame "]},{"question":"12. The cargo compartment APU warning horn can be inhibited during ground operations by the_____switch on the Entrance Light Panel.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-193(N)","responses":["OFF\/ARM","AGENT DISCH","ORIDE","INTL HORN INHIBIT "]},{"question":"13. If FIREX AGENT DISCHARGE 1 POWER CB on_____the is open, the_____will be inoperative.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2-395(C)","responses":["overhead panel, APU Fire Agent DISCH switch","right EPC, APU warning system","left EPC, the APU warning system","overhead panel, the APU fire and overspeed CAWS aural warning "]},{"question":"14. If an individual fuel tank indicator on the overhead is inoperative, the totalizer shows","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Fig : 1 -53 (N)","responses":["Correct total fuel","A blan k window","A series of dashes","Estimated fuel "]},{"question":"15. When fuel quantities drop below approximately ____ lbs for the inboard tanks and _____ lbs for the outboard tanks, the respective transfer pumps become uncovered and ineffective.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Fig 1 -54(N)","responses":["37,400; 24,500","28,000; 12,000","16,000; 4,000","27,500; 16,000 "]},{"question":"16. With no source of electrical power to the aircraft and the battery switch OFF, only the _____ bus is powered since it is connected dir ectly to the batteries.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-381","responses":["AC Transfer","Battery","Battery Direct","DC Transfer "]},{"question":"17. The electrical system is normally operated in the _____ mode with generators No. 1 and No. 2 supplying left side power and generators No. 3 and No. 4 supplying right side power.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-355","responses":["Parallel","Alternate parallel","Split-parallel","Linked"]},{"question":"18. The battery switch must be ON to provide battery power to the _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-368(N)","responses":["Transformer rectifiers","Emergency buses","Transfer buses","AC buses"]},{"question":"19. As a minimum, the batteries are designed to provide emergency power for up to ____ of operation.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-381(N)","responses":["15 minutes","45 minutes","One half-hour","One hour"]},{"question":"20. The aircraft batteries provide power to the _____ which provides power to the AC Emergency Bus.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-351","responses":["Static inverter","Transformer rectifier","AC cross tie relay","Generator control unit "]},{"question":"21. OBIGGS II: If there is a total loss of electrical power during high pressure pneumatic air supply operation, ____ may result.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-647A(C)","responses":["OBBIGS manifold failure","Fuselage fire","A hung start","Wing manifold failure "]},{"question":"22. The ____ normally supplies conditioned air to the flight compartment, crew rest area, and avionics cooling system. Trim air regulator","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para: 1 -668","responses":[" Trim air regulator ","Ram air duct","Left air conditioning pack","Right air conditioning pack "]},{"question":"23. If flight through contaminated air is experienced with the air conditioning pack(s) operating, the conditioned airflow used for avionics cooling _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-706(W)","responses":["Is unaffected","Will be contaminated","Is filtered","Is partially filtered "]},{"question":"24. If ambient temperatures are above _____, avionics cooling air flow must be supplied from conditioned air augmentation (APU or air conditioner ground unit).","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-723(N)","responses":["100 degrees F","95 degrees F","90 degrees F","85 degrees F "]},{"question":"25. (Pressurization) If the primary controller malfunctions or fails, the","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-735","responses":["system can be semi -automatically controlled during climbs and descents","system must be manually controlled","monitor controller automatically performs the function of the primary controller","other automatic controller must be manually selected "]},{"question":"26. The cabin pressurization SEMI mode controls cabin pressure according to","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-738","responses":["The baro -corrected altitude set in the LDG ALT -FT display window","An optimum schedule determined by the A\/PDMC","A schedule of 3000 ft. AGL along the mission computer flight plan","The altitude set in the window on the AFCS panel adjusted for terrain elevation from the NAV database "]},{"question":"27. If the cabin pressure differential exceeds 8.2 delta P, the ____ will automatically open.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-745","responses":["Negative pressure relief valves","Cabin pressure relief valves","FEDS hatches","Maintenance\/ditching hatch "]},{"question":"28. A self -contained ice detector located in the No. ____ engine inlet detects ice formation on a sensing element within the detector strut.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-770","responses":["1","2","3","4"]},{"question":"29. Engine anti-ice provides icing protection to the engine fan blades.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-782","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"30. The primary purpose of the transfer pump is to ____ in the event of No 2 or No 3 engine loss","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-820","responses":["Assist in cargo door\/ramp closing","Assist in landing gear retraction","A & B","None of the above "]},{"question":"31. When the RAT is the sole means of hydraulic pressure, do not slow below ____ as the RAT may stall and result in loss of aircraft control","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-834(W)","responses":["150 KCAS","200 KCAS","180 KCAS","130 KCAS "]},{"question":"32. The HSC determines the on demand pump operation in the following sequence of priority for hydraulic system No. 3","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-842","responses":["Primary, secondary, XFER, AUX pump","Primary, secondary, AUX, XFER pump","Primary, secondary, XFER, AUX pump, RAT","Primary, secondary, XFER pump, RAT "]},{"question":"33. If steering commands from the tillers and rudder pedals are in disagreement","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-881","responses":["The rudder command will be overridden.","The tiller command will be overridden.","The system blends the rates to provide steering","The greater command is used "]},{"question":"34. If the nose gear torque link is disconnected:","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-884(C)","responses":["Rudder pedals will not move","Nose wheel steering is not available","The nosewheel will not center upon retraction","EOCS is not available "]},{"question":"35. Which hydraulic system powers the normal brakes?","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-886","responses":["No. 1","No. 2","No. 3","No. 4 "]},{"question":"36. If ground speed on the MFD ND appears excessive:","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C-17A-1 Para: 1-893(W)","responses":["No action is required","All four IRUs should be realigned if on the ground","In-flight turn off the IRU being used for navigation","Re-align only the IRU in large font on the appropriate NAV SENSORS page"]},{"question":"37. In the event of large disparity between the IRU ground speed and the anti-skid brake controller sensed ground speed, braking capability will be reduced. If in flight, accomplish the landing using ____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-893(W)","responses":["Normal procedures","One brake inoperative procedures","Landing with Erroneous Ground Speed procedure.","Anti -skid inop procedures "]},{"question":"38. Pitch Reference Trim is available ____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-1007, 1 -1007(N)","responses":["Only with APPR mode engaged","With the FCS ACTR Panel PITCH TRIM switch in EFCS","With the FCS ACTR Panel PITCH TRIM switch in MECH","B & C "]},{"question":"39. If the ____ fails, automatic ground spoilers may not deploy during a rejected takeoff or subsequent landing.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-1065A(W)","responses":["TOGA switch","Speedbrake\/DLC switch","GND SPLR\/LAPES switch","Autothrottle disengage button "]},{"question":"40. Which of the following will not disengage the autopilot?","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-1182","responses":["Movement of the mechanical STAB TRIM handles","Retracting slats while the AFCS is engaged in TOGA mode","Aircraft exceeds 37 degree angle of bank","Actuating the flap index switch before engaging Approach Mode "]},{"question":"41. In frontside flight the default or basic mode for the AFCS pitch axis is the ____ mode.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-1214","responses":["Altitude select or capture","Vertical Speed\/Altitude Hold","Speed Hold or select","Split axis or turbulence "]},{"question":"42. The Alpha Speed function provides flight guidance and\/or control to limit minimum airspeed to configuration Alpha Speed, which provides safe buffet or stall margin for the existing aircraft configuration (flaps, slats, thrust level, weight and altitude).","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-1237","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"43. You may modify an RNAV or GPS route waypoint's lateral definition after loading from the WWNDB.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C-17A-1 Para: 1-1297A","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"44. The F\/D Traffic Collision Avoidance System (TCAS) submode is engaged by pressing the ____ when a TCAS Resolution Advisory (RA) is present and the A\/R mode is not engaged.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-1304","responses":["PPI button on the MFD","AP disengage switch on either control stick","TCAS button on the MCK","TOGA button "]},{"question":"45. When the FPV drift angle exceeds the limit of the HUD or PFD field of view, pitch information from the flashing FPV is ______ and only the ______ FPV symbol will provide correct vertical path information.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-1357(W)","responses":["Unusable, caged","Useable, actual","Unusable, actual","Useable, caged "]},{"question":"46. If entering a tactical environment immediately after takeoff, TACTICAL can be selected on the GPWS\/TAWS CONTROL page, but the displays will not switch to tactical until the ____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Fig 1 -246","responses":["Aircraft is farther than 15nm from the runway","Aircraft is above 1500 feet AGL","Aircraft is above 2500 feet AGL","Either A or B "]},{"question":"47. There are ____ smoke detectors located on the aircraft.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-1492","responses":["6","12","22","34 "]},{"question":"48. A target aircraft is within 6NM and could be potentially hazardous. This is ____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-1500","responses":["Other Traffic","Proximate Traffic","A Traffic Advisory (TA)","A Resolution Advisory (RA) "]},{"question":"49. The PPI SKE and ND MAP formats depict only ____ altitudes for TCAS traffic.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Fig 1 -252 #8","responses":["Absolute","Actual","AGL","Relative "]},{"question":"50. On the CMDS, ____ mode operates the same as the AUTO mode.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Fig 1 -257 #8","responses":["STBY","MAN","SEMI","BYP "]},{"question":"51. (IRCM) The laser is invisible and can injure eyes or skin within ____ feet for a single aft turret or ____ feet if the two forward turrets are installed.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-1566(W)","responses":["150; 175","162; 185","175; 197","187; 200 "]},{"question":"52. The Stall Warning System provides stick shaker and aural \u201cSTALL\u201d alerts to pilots when flight conditions (airspeed) approach what range?","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-1128","responses":[".95 -1.05 Vs","1.05 -1.15 Vs","Vmma u2013 Vne","1.33 -1.433 Vs "]},{"question":"53. Which action will not re -arm spoilers for RTO mode during touch and go landings?","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-1082","responses":["Moving all four throttles to the idle reverse detent","Momentarily pressing the TOGA switch","Advancing at least three throttle levers past a threshold of 60 degrees","Positioning the flap\/slat handle to any new detent "]},{"question":"54. Block 17: The MC can only perform a predictive RAIM (P -RAIM) check for destination waypoints that have a(n) ____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-2008C","responses":["WWNDB instrument approach procedure loaded","manually entered FAF","WAAS transmitter","fixed or advisory time constraint"]},{"question":"55. (APS150) What mode would be selected on the Radar Control Panel to see rainfall inside\/behind areas of turbulence?","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-2103(C)","responses":["GAIN MAX","MAP1","WX AUTO","WX MAN "]},{"question":"56. The ramp blowdown system may not function if the weight on the ramp exceeds ____ pounds.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-2187","responses":["5,250","10,275","15,750","20,750 "]},{"question":"57. When in VOR and TAC modes, the MC uses a ____ delay to compensate for temporary signal irregularities while transiting the ground station\u2019s cone of confusion. During the delay, the MC uses its last valid data from the NAVAID for guidance .","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-1296D (C)","responses":["10 second","30 second","60 second","5 minute"]},{"question":"58. When the CREW OXY LOW message illuminates on the WAP, it indicates","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-2296","responses":["Oxygen quantity remaining in the passenger converter is 2.5 liters or less","Oxygen quantity is less than 7.5 liters or supply pressure is below 60 +\/- 5 psi","Oxygen quantity remaining in the crew converter is 2.5 liters or less","Oxygen quantity is less than 5 liters or supply pressure is below 60 +\/- 5 psi "]},{"question":"59. The passenger oxygen system contains one ____ liter passenger converter and one ____ liter auxiliary converter.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-2308","responses":["75; 75","75; 25","25; 75","25; 25 "]},{"question":"60. APS -150 Weather Radar: For an aircraft cruising at or above 29,000 feet, when will existing weather be depicted as non- relevant (striped)?","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-2096","responses":["When actual weather is not within +\/ - 4,000 feet relative to aircraftu2019s actual\/projected altitude","When actual weather is below 25,000 feet","When a MC altitude constraint is above actual weather","A & B "]},{"question":"61. What is the total number of life rafts installed in the FEDS areas?","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-2339","responses":["Five","Two","Three","Four "]},{"question":"62. There are normally ____ first aid kits installed on the aircraft with provisions for ____ total.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-2346","responses":["9; 18","6; 18","6; 26","6; 102 "]},{"question":"63. There are a total of ____ fire extinguishers onboard the aircraft with ____ in the cockpit and ____ in the crew rest area.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-2348","responses":["6; 2; 1","9; 2; 1","9; 2; 2","12; 2; 2 "]},{"question":"64. L or R FUEL HEAVY is displayed on the WAP at ____ pound wing differential.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 1-215","responses":["4,000","12,000","8,000","28,000"]},{"question":"65. During high ambient air temperatures and reverse idle conditions, primary TOLD and allowable cargo load calculations may be overly restrictive. Use secondary TOLD to compare against primary TOLD to determine if allowable cargo load is overly restrictive.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2-10(N)","responses":["TRUE","FALSE "]},{"question":"66. (OBIGGS II) If the bleed air manifold is pressurized with any WCC- OBGxxxx fault displayed, depressurize it immediately and accomplish the ____ in Section III.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2-36 Step 22(W)","responses":["OBIGGS Filter Fire Hazard","Manifold Failure","OBIGGS MCD","Avionics Overheat "]},{"question":"67. Do not change the ENGINE IGNITION source during engine start. Switching sources may result in a","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2-51 Step 3(C)","responses":["Hot Start","Hung Start","Tailpipe fire","Sheared starter "]},{"question":"68. Select engine anti-ice on when temperature (SAT) is ____ degrees C or below and dew point and temperature are within ____ degrees C of each other or dew point is not available.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2-51 Step 12","responses":["8 ; 2","10 ; 3","9 ; 2","11; 3 "]},{"question":"69. For an RSC greater than ____ and an RCR less than ____, the actual runway required for takeoff\/landing could exceed runway available.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2-296 Step 20( W)","responses":[".01, 12",".01, 23",".00, 5",".00, 12 "]},{"question":"70. The aircraft is capable of backing up a ____% slope at a gross weight of ____ lbs (sea level, 90*F).","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2 -58","responses":["1; 502,100","1.5; 585,000","2; 502,100","2; 586,000"]},{"question":"71. To prevent damage to the reverse interlock solenoids, do not move the throttle levers beyond the reverse idle detent until\r\n_____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C-17A-1 Para: 2-62 Step 2(C)","responses":["The pilot not flying says its OK","Either the REV indication is illuminated on the MFD's or until the solenoids are heard to release","Betty says \"thrust reversers deployed\"","The nose wheel makes contact with the runway"]},{"question":"72. Abrupt use of brakes when backing the aircraft should be avoided to prevent","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2-62 Step 4(C)","responses":["The aircraft from setting on its tail","Brake failure","Damage to main landing gear tires","Spatial disorientation "]},{"question":"73. Do not attempt takeoff with any hydraulic reservoir temperature indicating less than ____ degrees C. Low rudder temperature indicates insufficient rate of rudder deflection to correct for an engine failure on takeoff.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2-71 Step 3(W)","responses":["-17","0","7","-7 "]},{"question":"74. The best climb gradient speeds are ____ for 0\/EXT, and ____ for UP\/RET.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2-89(N)","responses":["VMCG, VNE","VMCO, VMFR","VMFR\/VMMA, VMSR\/VMMA","VR,VCEF"]},{"question":"75. Pressing SC ZERO whenever the IRUs are in the ON position erases encryption keys, almanac and position information, forcing the ____ to reacquire. It will take much longer than normal on the next power up for the ____ to synchronize.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2-300 Step 12","responses":["IRUs, IRUs","RADIO UPDATE, IRUs","(C)GPS, (C)GPS","(M)GPS, (M)GPS "]},{"question":"76. If a GPWS\/TAWS aural or visual warning is received during an approach in Instrument Meteorological Conditions (IMC), ____. Exceptions will be annotated in command guidance.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2-134(W)","responses":["Execute a missed approach or go around","Check radar altimeter and continue if at a safe altitude","Check GPWS since it may be malfunctioning","Confirm your position with approach control and continue if you are on a published segment of the approach "]},{"question":"77. Approach to Assault Landing: No later than 300 feet AGL:","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2-151","responses":["The PF will engage PACAH","If the aircraft is not stable when passing through 300 feet, accomplish a go -around","The PM will deselect the FD","Both A & B "]},{"question":"78. On Extended Range aircraft with more than pounds total fuel, delay braking until nose gear touchdown unless there is less than pounds of fuel in the four extended range compartments combined.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2-272","responses":["185,000; 1,000","185,000; 4,000","165,000; 1,000","165,000; 4,000 "]},{"question":"79. If AGS does not deploy on landing, DLC spoilers are available to manually deploy ____ of AGS effectiveness.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2-275(N)","responses":["25 percent","5 percent","50 percent","15 percent "]},{"question":"80. The Standard Departure Profile uses a select MC data element, ____, and aero performance data, rather than an MC calculated solution, to validate the aircraft flight path meets or exceeds a given climb gradient when flown as published.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2 -91 A","responses":["CLB RATE \/ ALT 4 ENG","CFL","MC COF: ACT","MC COF: REQ "]},{"question":"81. If APU is inoperative, ensure either a ____ is in place or ____ connected before shutting down the last engine.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2 -289 Step 2(N)","responses":["loadmaster, air conditioning cart","maintenance crew chief, ground power unit","fire guard\/fire extinguisher, air cart","fire truck, lavatory service vehicle"]},{"question":"82. Operating engines in idle reverse thrust for extended periods during high OATs may cause one or more engine FIREX bottles to discharge uncommanded.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C-17A-1 Para: 2-296 Step 13(C)","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"83. If any doors\/hatches are opened, or if an immediate takeoff is not planned, the ____ or ____ checklist is required in lieu of the Full Stop Taxi -Back Checklist.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2-298","responses":["En Route Stop, Before Leaving Aircraft","Before Takeoff, Engine Shutdown","Operational Stop, After Landing","Cockpit Pre -flight, Before Taxi "]},{"question":"84. If the starter valve will not close after engine start (light remains illuminated more than 30 seconds after the button pops out), which of the following actions could result in a starter failure?","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2 -668 Step 8(C)","responses":["Selecting another ignition system","Pulling out the starter valve push- button","Shutting down the engine after removing the bleed air supply","Shutting down the engine before removing the bleed air supply "]},{"question":"85. Delay engine starter re -engagement for ____ once N2 RPM indication is lost from the MFD engine display to ensure that engine rotation has stopped.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2 -672 Step 5 (C )","responses":["20 seconds","30 seconds","40 seconds","1 minute "]},{"question":"86. (IRCM) Ground operations longer than ____ minutes with the outside air temperature above 38 degrees C \/ 100 degrees F may result in TX x FAIL and degraded IRCM performance.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2-854(C)","responses":["25","10","5","60 "]},{"question":"87. If AN\/ARC -210 COM radio prolonged loss of contact (PLOC) is suspected or experienced while flying in Europe, which of the following actions should you take?","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-68E","responses":["Immediately squawk 7600","Disable squelch","Request relay from another aircraft and\/or attempt ATC contact on Guard using any radio","All of the above "]},{"question":"88. In addition to an engine fire, disintegration, seizure or uncontrollable overspeed, the ENGINE FIRE\/EMERGENCY ENGINE SHUTDOWN Checklist will be run with ____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-112","responses":["Severe compressor stall or engine vibration","Engine\/pylon fuel leak","Uncontrollable EGT","All of the above"]},{"question":"89. If an engine reverts to the N2 mode, all engine responses are normal except ____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-122","responses":["No reverse thrust is available during landing ground roll","Touch and go landings are prohibited","That no overspeed protection is provided","The engine will lock 85% N2 "]},{"question":"90. If the N1 RPM indication drops to zero or all di splays are blank, ____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-129(W)","responses":["The EEC has failed","This could indicate a catastrophic engine failure","Shutdown and restart the engine to reset the EEC","The EEC is running an internal test and the displays will return in 60 seconds"]},{"question":"91. A Four Engine Flameout is most likely to occur when flying through","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-113A","responses":["Heavy rain","Hail and icing","Volcanic ash","All of the above "]},{"question":"92. If ALS is flashing when the aircraft reference symbol representing aircraft pitch attitude is within ____ degrees of the flight path, the ALS is erroneously activating.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-240","responses":["10","16","8","12 "]},{"question":"93. Four Engine Flameout: Wings level C -17 glide ratio is _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3 -113B Step 5","responses":["2.6 NM\/1000 ft","1 NM\/1000 ft","3.1 NM\/1000 ft","4.5 NM\/1000 ft"]},{"question":"94. Engine Failure During Takeoff: The MC calculates 3 -engine climb gradient capability based on the use of ____ power. After liftoff increase power on operating engines to ____ thrust as required to meet 3-engine climb gradient requirements.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-135","responses":["MAX, MAX","MAX, INT","MCT, INT","DRT, MAX"]},{"question":"95. If experiencing severe engine vibration is during flight,","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-192","responses":["Execute a Precautionary Engine Shutdown","Advance the engine throttles one at a time (from left to right) to isolate the vibrating engine","Immediately shut down the engine using the Engine Fire\/Emergency Engine Shutdown Checklist","Retard the engine throttles one at a time (from left to right) to isolate the vibrating engine "]},{"question":"96. For PITCH AUTHORITY CAWS alert while airborne,","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-246","responses":["Let go of the stick to allow autotrim to regain control","Turn the pitch trim switch on the overhead FCS panel to MECH","Depressurize hydraulic systems 2 and 3","Slow the aircraft and simultaneously split the STAB TRIM handles "]},{"question":"97. If a MASTER CAUTION and an EFCS MCD cue annunciate during the takeoff roll, Allow 1 second between button presses","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-272","responses":["If below Vgo, reject the takeoff if possible.","If takeoff is continued, the PM will repeatedly press the EFCS RESET button as soon as EFCS MCD is annunciated. Allow 1 second between button presses ","Ensure FROZEN GAINS appears on the MCD STATUS page","A & B "]},{"question":"98. FCC FIXED GAINS: Large abrupt rudder inputs at speeds over ____ KCAS can overstress the vertical stabilizer and rudders.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-303(C)","responses":["250","300","225","200"]},{"question":"99. Fuel dump above ____ feet may cause engine flameout due to loss of fuel pressure.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-350(W)","responses":["20,000","15,000","17,500","10,000 "]},{"question":"100. Normally fuel dump is accomplished with the center separation valve closed. Confirm that both lights illuminate or","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-352(C)","responses":["Check for open feeder circuit breakers","Cycle the dump switch from off to on","Open the separation valve immediately","Discontinue fuel dumping and land as soon as practical "]},{"question":"101. Loss of a hydraulic system may occur when the quantity decreases causing the HYD QTY LOW X or HYD QTY LOW X, Y WAP message(s) to be displayed. If this message appears,","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-389","responses":["Put the flaps down while there is still some pressure","Be prepared for complete loss of flight controls","Decrease power on the engine to slow the pumps down","Shut off all pumps within the affected system "]},{"question":"102. Primary flight controls are powered by how many hydraulic systems?","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-389(N)","responses":["1","2","3","4 "]},{"question":"103. BLOCK 19->: Use the lower of the following two altitudes to determine the planned 3 -engine acceleration altitude:","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-137E","responses":["MC ACC ALT, MIN IFR Altitude","1000 feet AFE, ODP Altitude","SDP LOA, MSA","MOCA, OROCA "]},{"question":"104. When using alternate brake system, increase mission computer generated landing or ground roll distance by","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-425(W)","responses":["500 feet","1000 feet","25%","50% "]},{"question":"105. What is the aircraft configuration for an emergency descent?","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-505","responses":["Flaps 1\/2; gear down; throttles - IDLE","Speed brakes - Deployed; gear down; N2 - 85 percent","Clean; throttles - IDLE; Airspeed - 310 knots","Throttles - IDLE or IDLE REV; Speed Brakes - Deployed; Airspeed - As Required "]},{"question":"106. A personnel restraining harness or parachute is required to be worn ____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-507 step 7 (W)","responses":["During all emergencies that may require a bailout","When inspecting aircraft doors after an in -flight door\/hatch warning","During low level flight below 500 AGL","Only when directed by the aircraft commander"]},{"question":"107. During a rejected takeoff, ____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-521 step 3 (C)","responses":["Use MAX reverse on all operating engines","Asymmetrical reverse thrust should be used with caution","Do not use reverse thrust","Use MAX reverse on the side with good engines and MAX brakes on the other side "]},{"question":"108. There is a maximum of ____ engine start attempts in one hour, followed by a ____ minimum cooling period.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 5 -17","responses":["2; 30 minute","3; 45 minute","4; 1 hour","5; 1 hour "]},{"question":"109. Engine rotation will be completely stopped before the starter is re -engaged. The exception to this is the Engine Clearing Procedure, when the starter may be re-engaged after N2 RPM has decreased below ____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 5 -18","responses":["18- 24%","20%","0, the starter must always completely stop","10% "]},{"question":"110. The maximum time limit at MAX\/DRT thrust is ____ minutes when not needed for engine failure on takeoff, or engine out go -around for obstacle clearance.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 F ig : 5 -1","responses":["5","10","7","There is no maximum time limit at MAX\/DRT "]},{"question":"111. Maximum EGT for engine start is ____ degrees.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 F ig : 5 -1","responses":["650","500","495","450"]},{"question":"112. The APU starter operating limit is ____ minute and any APU starter engagement is considered a start attempt. ____ starts may be attempted per rolling one hour cycle with a minimum delay of ____ minutes between attempts.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 5 -21","responses":["1, 4, 10","1, 5, 10","1, 3, 5","1, 4, 5"]},{"question":"113. The recommended minimum airspeed for in -flight reverse thrust is ____ or Vmma, whichever is higher.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 F ig : 5 -6 Note 3","responses":["225","200","250","300 "]},{"question":"114. The maximum airspeed for extending the slats is ____ ; for retracting is ____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 F ig : 5 -6","responses":["270; 270","280; 280","270; 280","280; 270 "]},{"question":"115. What is the maximum airspeed allowable for extending the landing gear?","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 F ig : 5 -6","responses":["225","250","275","300 "]},{"question":"116. Bank angles greater than ____ degrees are not recommended. The maximum bank angle is ____ degrees.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 5-60B","responses":["30; 45","45; 60","50; 60","60; 70 "]},{"question":"117. During taxi with speed greater than 20 knots with symmetric thrust (15 knots with asymmetric thrust), a 20 degree nose wheel steering angle limit applies if gross weight exceeds ____ lbs or with more than ____ lbs of fuel.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 F ig : 5 -10","responses":["490,000; 135,000","502,100; 135,000","490,000; 165,000","502,100; 165,000 "]},{"question":"118. The maximum taxi speed for paved taxiways is ____ knots; maximum taxiway speed for semi -prepared taxiways is ____ knots with gross weight\/fuel weight less than or equal to 435,000\/82,000 lbs respectively.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 F ig : 5 -10\/5 -11","responses":["30; 40","40; 30","30; 20","20; 30 "]},{"question":"119. Tire cord limits: The maximum wear limit (MWL) is defined as the exposure of the ____ cord layer plus ____ additional \tlandings. third, two","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 5 -86","responses":[" third, two ","third, five","second, five","second, three "]},{"question":"120. The maximum allowable crosswind for landing is ____ knots.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 5 -92","responses":["30","40","25","35 "]},{"question":"121. The maximum landing touchdown sink rate for a steep approach (502,100 lbs) is ____ feet\/min.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 F ig : 5 -16","responses":["1100","660","500","1000 "]},{"question":"122. If a stall occurs","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 6 -15","responses":["Apply smooth, but positive forward stick","Increase thrust to MAX and retract speedbrakes (if required)","Roll input to level the wings","All of the above "]},{"question":"123. APS150 Weather Radar: The Magenta areas represent areas of ____ turbulence and should always be avoided","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 7 -6A","responses":["Light to Moderate","Moderate to Severe","Clear Air","Extreme "]},{"question":"124. Flight through extremely heavy rain, particularly with low thrust settings (< 45% N1),","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 7 -65E(W)","responses":["May result in flameout of one or more engines","May cause fluctuations in engine performance","Should be accomplished using A & B ignition","Provides an acceptable means of tactical threat avoidance "]},{"question":"125. ____ should be used for flight in known or anticipated turbulent air.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 7-66A(C)","responses":["The turbulence mode of the auto pilot","Extreme caution","Engine ignition","Slow speeds"]},{"question":"126. During wind shear recovery, unless a sink rate exists, do not exceed ____ degrees of pitch below ____ feet AGL.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 7-81(W)","responses":["12; 200","10-15; 300","12-15; 200","15; 200"]},{"question":"127. Failure to use engine anti-ice when icing conditions are present may result in ____","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 7-119(C)","responses":["Engine damage due to ice ingestion","Engine flameout","Reversion to the N1 mode","Severe compressor stalls "]},{"question":"128. Takeoff will not be attempted with over ____ inch(es) of wet snow, slush and\/or water, or ____ inch(es) of dry snow on the runway.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 7-145(W)","responses":["1\/4, 2","1, 3","1\/2, 4","1\/3, 4\/3 "]},{"question":"129. Icing and Cold Weather Operation: Taxi speed should be as low as practical on slippery surfaces and taxi speed of knots or \tless","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 7-134","responses":["10","5","15","12 "]},{"question":"130. Failure to periodically perform the ground ice shedding procedure can result in damage to the engines. If more than ____ minutes have expired since engine start and icing conditions persist, delay takeoff until the procedure is accomplished.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 7-140(C)","responses":["5","15","30","20"]},{"question":"131. If excessive ice formations remain on the aircraft after climbing through an icing layer, level off and increase airspeed to obtain at least ____ or higher.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 7-151","responses":["+3 *C TAT","+6 *C TAT","-10 *C SAT","+10 *C TAT"]},{"question":"132. Under no circumstance will flights be planned through _____ icing conditions. Aircraft operation in _____ icing conditions may be tolerated for short periods of time but evasive action should be undertaken to exit icing conditions as soon as practicable.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 7-144(W)","responses":["Moderate; moderate","Forecast moderate; light","Forecast or known severe; moderate","Suspected clear; light"]},{"question":"133. Cold weather\/ ground icing conditions: Use of autothrottles for takeoff is strongly encouraged. If an EPR probe icing condition should occur, the autothrottles will ignore the erroneous EPR and maintain the correct power setting via computed throttle leve l","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 7-147","responses":["TRUE","FALSE "]},{"question":"134. The anti-ice system is designed ____. Therefore, the anti-ice system must be activated before ice buildup","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 7-153(C)","responses":["To prevent ice buildup rather than remove it once it forms","As a deicing system","To be used in light icing conditions only","For use in severe icing conditions"]},{"question":"135. If icing conditions are expected during the descent, engine anti-ice, wing anti-ice, and windshield anti-ice will be turned on at least ____ feet above the expected icing level in order to provide adequate warm up time.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 7-163","responses":["5,000","10,000","8,000","2,000 "]},{"question":"136. The Pre-Takeoff Contamination Check is required if holdover time has expired or if freezing precipitation is occurring on an aircraft that was not anti -iced. The contamination check must be completed from OUTSIDE the aircraft within ____ minutes prior to takeoff.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 7-181","responses":["15","10","5","20 "]},{"question":"137. After deicing is complete, it will take up to ____ for the outflow valve to fully open and lower the cabin pressure to the point where the crew entry door will open normally.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 7-222 step 12(N)","responses":["5 minutes","90 seconds","3 minutes","30 seconds "]},{"question":"138. Intermediate Thrust Rating (INT) is ____. This is the recommended rating for engine-out climbs.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 -1 Para : 2-7","responses":["The maximum thrust approved for the engine","The highest thrust certified for continuous use","The highest thrust recommended for normal climb","The minimum thrust required to safely perform a takeoff"]},{"question":"139. Maximum Continuous Thrust (MCT) rating is ____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 -1 Para : 2-9","responses":["The maximum thrust approved for the engine","The thrust recommended for engine -out climb","The highest thrust recommended for normal climb operation","The maximum thrust required to safely perform a takeoff"]},{"question":"140. Go speed (VGO) is the lowest of ____, ____, or ____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 -1 Para : 3 -26","responses":["V1, VCEF, VBO","VMCO, VMCG, VMCA ","VROT, VR, VBMAX","VMFR, VMSR, VTD"]},{"question":"141. The aircraft static air temperature shall not be used for takeoff calculation since heat radiation picked up by the sensing element can cause considerable error. Using an incorrect temperature may result in an unsafe takeoff.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 -1 Para: 3 -65(W)","responses":["TRUE","FALSE "]},{"question":"142. Fluid Holdover Times: The C -17 is considered a(n) ____ aircraft.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 7-186(N)","responses":["aluminum","composite","piezoelectric","ceramic"]},{"question":"143. A lineup distance penalty must be applied anytime the takeoff is not commenced from the beginning of the usable runway from a taxiway. Apply a standard distance of _____ feet to account for turning the aircraft around on the runway or accessing the runway from a taxiway.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 -1 Para : 3-112","responses":["100","80","250","200"]},{"question":"144. Holding: The normal C -17 holding airspeed is ____ , but not less than VMMA.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 2-128","responses":["Long Range Cruise","230 knots","an airspeed derived from a command -approved planning and execution program","B or C "]},{"question":"145. Landing is not permitted with tailwinds greater than ____ or headwinds greater than ____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 -1 Para : 9-117(W)","responses":["10, 10","15, 10","10, 40","10, 15 "]},{"question":"146. MC TOLD: If VBO LDG DIST exceeds ____ and LDG DIST is valid, VBO LDG DIST is highlighted and VBO LD DIST\/nnn.nGW (MSG) is generated. If VBO GND ROLL exceeds ____ and GND ROLL is valid, VBO GND ROLL is highlighted and VBO GD ROLL\/nnn.nGW (MSG)","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 -2 Para : 1-855A","responses":["CFL, CFL","RWY AVAIL, RWY AV AIL","GND ROLL + 500 feet, GND ROLL + 500 feet","TORA, TODA "]},{"question":"147. GPWS Mode 4C (gear down, flaps 1\/2 detent or less and below 500 feet radar altitude) is inoperative when ____ .","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 -2 Para : 1-208(W)","responses":["Performing circling approaches","TAWS is active","TACTICAL mode is selected ","When flying a \"frontside\" approach"]},{"question":"148. GPWS warnings\/alerts shall remain ON during flight.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 -2 Para: 1 -209(W)","responses":["TRUE","FALSE "]},{"question":"149. (Thrust Reverser Status, 3L) When a SPAM runway is selected for emergency return or landing, the MC adds another thrust reverser selection for four engines (4ENG). 4ENG assumes","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 -2 Para: 1 -828","responses":["two engines in forward thrust and two engines in idle reverse","four engines in idle reverse for 33% of the landing roll out","loss of one engine, one engine in idle reverse, and symmetric engines in maximum reverse","all four engines operating and in maximum reverse thrust "]},{"question":"150. During Degraded Modes, _____ use(s) the last valid altitude and heading data they received prior to the Degraded","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 -2 Para: 3 -11(N)","responses":["Advise ATC as necessary.","IFF and TCAS","Weather Radar","IRUs","TOLD "]},{"question":"151. If both MC's fail, fully automatic control of cabin pressurization is lost.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C-17A-1-2 Para: 3-23","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"152. The visual signal for a BREAKAWAY is","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Fig : 8 -4","responses":["Tanker retracts and stows the boom during contact","Tanker flashes Pilot Director Lights and\/or turns lower Rotating Beacon ON","Tanker boom extended approximately 5 feet","Pilot Director Lights extinguished during contact. "]},{"question":"153. If the receiver overruns the tanker, the receiver will reduce airspeed to _____, and maintain track and altitude.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 8 -46","responses":["230 KCAS","255 KCAS or minimum maneuvering speed, whichever is lower","255 KCAS or minimum maneuvering speed, whichever is higher","Appropriate refueling speed or Vmma, whichever is lower "]},{"question":"154. _____ is the desired standard for daily air refueling operations.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 8 -54","responses":["Emission Option 1","Emission Option 2 ","Emission Option 3 ","Emission Option 4"]},{"question":"155. When the receiver pilot is closing and approaching the pre-contact position,","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 8-111(W)","responses":["It is mandatory to call \"Stable, Ready\" during Emission Option 2 operations","The receiver should use TCAS in TA\/RA mode until established in precontact","The receiver will stabilize in the precontact position and attain a zero rate of closure","The boom operator will trail the boom fully extended until the receiver approaches contact "]},{"question":"156. Tankers and receivers will begin monitoring designated radio frequencies no less than _____ minutes prior to the ARCT.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 8-118 Step 3","responses":["15","20","30","25"]},{"question":"157. During an air refueling BREAKAWAY, the receiver pilot should use caution not to overrun the tanker. If overrunning does occur, under no condition should _____, be made until positive separation has been attained.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-538 Step 1 (W)","responses":["An acceleration","A climb","A rejoin","A turn, either right or left "]},{"question":"158. A controlled tension brute force disconnect will be accomplished _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-561(C)","responses":["Only as a last resort","When directed by higher headquarters","For all normal disconnects","For training purposes only "]},{"question":"159. (Emergency Boom Latching Procedures) It is possible to cause structural damage to the air refueling boom and slipway by severe relative movement between the two aircraft when operating in override since the _____ are deactivated. The _____ must initiate all disconnects.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"1C -17A -1 Para : 3-563A (C)","responses":["Toggles; boom operator","Toggles; receiver pilot","Limit switches; receiver pilot","Limit switches; boom operator"]},{"question":"160. During the RV Delta (Point Parallel) procedure the receiver(s) will as possible, but no later than 50 nm range or the RVIP, whichever occurs first","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"ATP 56B Part 2 Annex 1D Para: 102 D d","responses":["Be established at 1000 ft below the assigned base AAR altitude when departing the RVIP","Enter the track via the RVIP and should aim to be at the RVIP at the RVCT","Aid the RV, when so equipped, by remaining in electronic contact on radar, A\/A TACAN, TCAS or other means as soon as possible, but no later than 50 nm range or the RVIP, whichever occurs first ","A & C "]},{"question":"161. Crewmembers enrolled in PCO, IAC, CPAD, and ACAD are exempt from quarterly phase training.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V1 Para : 4.9.1.3","responses":["TRUE","FALSE "]},{"question":"162. Which of the following results in an individual being declared NMR?","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V1 Para : 4.10","responses":["Failure to maintain flying currency.","Failure to complete semi -annual flying continuation training requirements.","Failure to complete ground continuation training requirements.","Any of the above. "]},{"question":"163. A member may also credit a Day Low Level (M055) each time they accomplish a NVG Low Level (NV00).","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V1 Para : 7.13 .1.6.5","responses":["TRUE","FALSE "]},{"question":"164. How many Receiver AR (R010) events may be accomplished per sortie?","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V1 Para : 7.14.22.6","responses":["One","Two","Three","Four "]},{"question":"165. Crew duty time and flight duty period both begin ______. (exception: msns launched from Alfa\/Bravo or self -alerting)","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V3 Para : 3.7.3, 3.13.1","responses":["1 hour after alert","At alert time","When the crew member arrives at the squadron","As designated by the aircraft commander "]},{"question":"166. The maximum flight duty period for a basic crew (including Basic +1) is _____ hours; for an augmented crew _____ hours.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V3 Para : 3.7.1.1, 3.7.1.2","responses":["12; 16","20; 24+45","16; 24","18; 24+45 "]},{"question":"167. Available crewmembers will assist in clearing during ____ and anytime the aircraft is below ____ feet MSL.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V3 Para : 5.6","responses":["taxi operations; 18,000","taxi operations; 10,000","taxi in congested areas; 10,000","taxi in congested areas; 18,000 "]},{"question":"168. Equipment will be properly secured and all crewmembers and passengers will be seated with seat belts and shoulder harnesses (shoulder harness does not apply to pax) fastened during taxi, takeoff, landing, AAR, and low levels unless crew duties dictate otherwise.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V3 Para : 5.7.2","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"169. With weather at CAT I minimums on a CAT I ILS, the pilot may not see the runway environment at DA; however, the initial portion of the approach lights may be visible. The pilot may continue to ____ HAT with reference to the approach lights only. The pilot may not descend below _____ feet above touchdown zone elevation using the approach lights as reference unless the red terminating bars or the red side row bars are distinctly visible and identifiable","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V3 Para : 5.11 Note 1","responses":["200; 200","200; 100","100; 100","100; 50 "]},{"question":"170. If on an instrument approach, the PM must still provide subsequent instrument advisory calls if the PF can maintain visual contact with the landing runway, and states \"Visual.\"","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V3 Para : 5.11 Note 4","responses":["TRUE","F ALSE "]},{"question":"171. Both pilots will VERIFY the intended changes prior to execution to include the correct mode is selected (e.g. ensure LNAV is selected when cleared to a point while on a heading).","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V3 Para : 5.15.2. 2","responses":["TRUE","FALSE "]},{"question":"172. Minimum runway\/taxiway widths for C -17 operations are:","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V3 Para : 5.18.1","responses":["150 ft runway, 90 ft taxiway","100 ft runway, 70 ft taxiway","90 ft runway, 50 ft taxiway","75 ft runway, 45 ft taxiway "]},{"question":"173. Do not taxi an aircraft within _____ feet of obstructions without wing walkers monitoring clearance between aircraft and obstructions. With wing walkers, avoid taxi obstructions by at least _____ feet.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V3 Para : 5.19.1","responses":["25; 10","25; 25","15; 10","10; 5"]},{"question":"174. Weather Minimums for Takeoff: What minimum visibility is required to depart on an operational mission in the absence of RVR readout?","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V3 Table 6.3","responses":["1000 meters","1\/2 mile","800 meters","B or C"]},{"question":"175. During flight, avoid thunderstorm activity by any means available by at least _____ NM at or above FL 230 and _____ NM below FL230.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V3 Para: 6.21.3.1, 6.2 1.3.2","responses":["10, 20","20, 10","15, 25","25, 15 "]},{"question":"176. Weather minimums for NVG departures for crewmembers who are non -current and\/or unqualified is ____. Current and qualified NVG aircrews may fly NVG departures weather down to ____(OG\/CC or equivalent may approve down to ____).","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V3 Para : 6.33.1","responses":["1000\/2; 500\/1; 300\/1","600\/2; 300\/1; 200\/ 1\/2 "," 1500\/3; 5 00\/2; 300\/ 1\/2 ","1500\/3; 600\/2; 300\/1"]},{"question":"177. Inflight Fuel Optimization: After takeoff, aircrews should determine and request to cruise at their optimum altitude. Optimum altitude can be calculated with ____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V3 Para : 14.5.1.1","responses":["the MC CRUISE PERFORMANCE page","the Pilot's Performance Advisory System (PPAS)","IAW AMC approved checklist insert OPTIMUM CRUISE ALTITUDES if PPAS is not available","B or C"]},{"question":"178. (IAP) Instrument approach RVR\/visibility and, if required, ceiling minimums will be as published for a category ____ aircraft. If approach speeds exceed 165 knots, the minimums for ____ category will be used.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V3 Para : 6.42.1","responses":["C; D","D; E","E; F","B; C "]},{"question":"179. If full flight instrumentation is not available and operational, aircraft are limited to a DH\/MDA based on ____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V3 Para : 6.42.4","responses":["Circling minimums, but no lower than 600 feet and 2 miles vis","Aircraft are limited to VMC operations only","A HAT of 300 feet and RVR 4000 or u00be mile visibility with no RVR","The lowest compatible non precision minimums "]},{"question":"180. Aircrews may fly NVG instrument approaches which transition to NVG landings with weather down to (OG\/CC or equivalent may approve down to ) or circling minimums (whichever is higher).","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V3 Para : 6.43.1","responses":["500\/1; 300\/1","300\/1; 200\/u00bd","500\/2; 300\/u00be","600\/2; 300\/1 "]},{"question":"181. If involved in a mishap or incident, pull the CVR power circuit breaker","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V3 Para : 6.49","responses":["Immediately after terminating the emergency.","After landing.","After landing and terminating the emergency.","Never."]},{"question":"182. Manual entry of waypoints using Latitude\/Longitude or Place\/Bearing is prohibited on any RNAV procedure.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V3 Para : 11.5.3.1","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"183. Destination Requirements (for filing purposes): File two alternates when:","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"11 -2C -17 V3 Para : 6.20.1","responses":["The forecast visibility (intermittent or prevailing) is less than published for the available DoD\/NACO precision approach","GPS is the only available NAVAID at destination","Radar is required for all available instrument approaches at destination","B or C"]},{"question":"184. Maximum on Ground (MOG) is based solely on parking space available.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"AFTTP 3 -3.C17 Para : 3.3.4","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"185. From the left seat an imaginary line drawn from the row of rivets inside the number _____ engine cowling at approximately the _____ o'clock position closely identifies 25-foot wingtip clearance.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"AFTTP 3-3.C17 Para: 3.2.3.4.1","responses":["1; 4","2; 4","1; 6","3; 4"]},{"question":"186. Which statement is TRUE for the following situation: You are preparing for engine running off\/onload operations and a thrust reverser will not extend:","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"AFTTP 3 -3.C17 Para : 3.2.5.2 (W)","responses":["Offload operations can be conducted if it is an outboard engine","ERO operations are absolutely not permitted","Shutdown of the engine should be considered prior to ERO operations","Symmetrical engines must be shut down "]},{"question":"187. When operating into semi -prepared runways, aircrews must input the numerical rolling friction factor (RFF) into the mission computer to calculate take-off data prior to landing.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"AFTTP 3 -3.C17 Para : 3.4.1.6.1","responses":["TRUE","FALSE "]},{"question":"188. Time Control: A rule of thumb for calculating actual Delta T for Climbs\/Descents is to apply a 1 minute correction to Delta T for every ____ feet of altitude to gain or lose. This ROT applies only when there are no waypoints between present position","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"AFTTP 3 -3.C17 Para : 4.5. 2.5.3","responses":["2,000","10,000","5,000","1,000 "]},{"question":"189. Taxi Centerline References: While taxiing the aircraft straight ahead, the position of the nosewheel is approximated by ____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"AFTTP 3 -3.C17 Para : 3.2.3.2","responses":["the inboard screw of the heads -up display (HUD)","the inboard leg of the pilot flying (PF)","the first inboard dot of the lateral deviation indicator in the HUD","all of the above"]},{"question":"190. Time Control (high altitude): Take ____ percent of TAS to determine how long a 360 -degree turn will take in minutes","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"AFTTP 3-3.C17 Para: 4.5.2.3.2","responses":["3","0.5","1","3.6"]},{"question":"191. ____ terrain masking is placing terrain behind the aircraft so it is difficult to distinguish the aircraft from the background. ____ terrain masking is putting the terrain between the aircraft and the threat.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"AFTTP 3 -3.C17 Para : 4.3.4.7.4","responses":["Direct; Military Crest","Indirect; Direct","45 Degree; Parallel Ridge","Perpendicular Ridge; Indirect "]},{"question":"192. Time Control (low altitude): Turn ____ degrees off course for 1 minute, then turn back to course on a ____ degree intercept for 1 minute. This allows the crew to intercept the original course and lose 1 minute.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"AFTTP 3 -3.C17 Para : 4.5.2.4.1","responses":["30, 30","45, 45","60, 60","90, 90 "]},{"question":"193. On a dry surface with symmetric engine thrust and no differential braking, the aircraft can execute a 180-degree turn in ____ feet.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"AFTTP 3 -3.C17 Para : 3.2.3.7","responses":["90","143","116","175 "]},{"question":"194. For low-altitude, level slowdowns, use of ground speed as a general rule of thumb. Add if above 280 KCAS to allow time to configure.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"AFTTP 3 -3.C17 Table 5.1","responses":["1%; 2NM","2% ; 1NM","1% ; 1NM","3% ; 2NM "]},{"question":"195. What approximate descent gradient can be obtained flying 230 KCAS and configured with Slats and Speed Brakes?","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"AFTTP 3 -3.C17 Table 5.3","responses":["300 ft\/NM","525 ft \/NM","950 ft\/NM","1480 ft\/NM "]},{"question":"196. Standard terminology for PM assault landing calls is ____ of the \"zone\".","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"AFTTP 3 -3.C17 Para : 5.5.5.4 .4.1","responses":["Front half, center, back half","Brick one, end","Front, middle, back","First third, middle third, last third "]},{"question":"197. A 45 degree bank turn decreases the aircraft's climb performance by ____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"AFTTP 3-3.C17 Table 5.6","responses":["3%","13%","29%","50%"]},{"question":"198. 1 on X AAR: During AAR with tanker formations, after receiving the scheduled on-load from the first tanker, descend in trail ____ the current tanker (____the next tanker).","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"AFTTP3 -3.C17 Para: 6.8.3","responses":["1000 feet below, 500 feet below","500 feet below, 1500 feet below","500 feet below, level with","1000 feet below, 1500 feet below "]},{"question":"199. In a tactical environment, a ____ is an established reference point from which the position of an object can be referenced by bearing (Magnetic) and range (NM).","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"AFTTP3 -3.C17 Para: A4.2 Brevity Codes","responses":["SARNEG","CHATTERMARK","BULLSEYE","POPEYE "]},{"question":"200. AAR Pre -departure Fuel Planning: Determine the minimum on-load required. Vary the AAR on -load amount until the ____ fuel or ____ fuel reaches zero, whichever occurs first. That amount is the minimum on-load required.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"AFTTP 3 -3.C17 Para : 6.2.2.4.","responses":["STORED, ID EXTRA","RECOVERY, UNID EXTRA","STORED, UNID EXTRA","ALTN, ID EXTRA "]},{"question":"201. As a rule of thumb (ROT) the C-17 is capable of refueling at maximum gross weight with KC -10 up to and including ___ and a KC -135 up to and including _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"AFTTP3 -3.C17 Para: 6.2.1 (N)","responses":["FL 210, FL 230","FL 240, FL 260","FL 340, FL 360","FL 180, FL 200 "]},{"question":"202. It is OK to say the color code corresponding to a radio frequency when checking in on the radio, i.e. \"THUG 17 checking in on GREEN 11.\"","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"AFTTP3-3.C17 Para: A7.3.1.1","responses":["True, it lets the Eye in Sky know you're on the correct frequency","False, you've now compromised the frequency"]}]}
